Guide to the Views of the Pacific Northwest
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Part II. Original order of scrapbook
  - Page 49
    - Page 53
      - [H.M.S. Satellite, Head of the Albirni Canal, North West Coast of Vancouver Island, Barclay Sound.] Pen and ink and watercolor, 26.4 x 42.7 cm., [1859 Mar 9] (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Page 55
    - [McMurtrie, William?] Three-masted side-wheeler. Pencil drawing, 17.6 x 26.3 cm., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Two masted ship with note "Drawn from memory by a [Jongas?] Indian (N W Coast of America) to the Northd. of Fort Simpson...." Pencil drawing, 16.3 x 14.2 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Page 57
    - Coastal landmarks, C. Frio and Rio de Janeiro. Pen and ink and watercolor drawings, 22.7 x 28.6 cm. (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Page 59
    - Coastal landmarks, Tierra del Fuego, Cape St. Vincent, Magdalena Island. Pen and ink and watercolor drawings, 22.7 x 28.5 cm. (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Page 60
    - Coastal landmarks, Capa Froward, Cape Providence, Cape Pillar. Pen and ink and watercolor drawings, 22.7 x 28.5 cm. (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Page 61
    - Coastal landmarks, East Falkland and Patagonian Mission House, Rappel Island. Pen and ink and watercolor drawing, 21.7 x 27.2 cm. (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Page 62
    - "Valparaiso." Photographic print, 16.3 x 20.9 cm., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Page 63
    - [Valparaiso.] Photographic print, 16.1 x 21 cm., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - [Valparaiso?] Photographic print, 9.6 x 20.8 cm., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - [Valparaiso?] Photographic print, 15.4 x 21.3 cm., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Page 64
    - Drawing of microorganisms "Found in phosphorescent seawater, magnified 120 diameters." Pen and ink and watercolor drawing, 12.6 x 17.9 cm. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Page 65
    - "Town of Stanley, Falkland Islands." Photographic print, 14.2 x 20.9 cm., 1857 Jul (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Lowther, Marcus. "[Chinchas?] The Defiance of N.Y. loading." Pen and ink drawing, 11.1 x 15.0 cm., 1854 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "Stanley Harbour, Falkland Island. H.M.S. Satellite at anchor." Photographic print, 10.6 x 5.8 cm., [1857 Feb] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Page 67
    - "The [stormy?] Petrel -- which surrounded the Satellite on the passage from Valparaiso to Calif." Pen and ink and gray wash drawing, 17.6 x 13.0 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - "The little bird which flew on the Satellite's [Port?] and was caught as in a cage when the [Port?] was lowered." Pen and ink and watercolor drawing, 8.5 x 19.0 cm., 1857 Apr 18 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - "No. 2. The same as No. 1 only a different view. H.M.S. Satellite." Pen and ink and watercolor drawing, 16.0 x 11.9 cm., [1857] Apr 16 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Page 69
    - Alden, J.M. Fort Vancouver, Oregon. Watercolor, 23.6 x 30.7 cm., [1854] (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Miscellany 1
    - Tucker, B. "The famous monastery of Megaspeleon...in ancient Achaia...." Pen and ink drawing, 13.2 x 19.3 cm., 1839 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Miscellany 2
    - Two story house. Photographic print, 15.4 x 20 cm., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Miscellany 3
    - Two story house with tree in front and woman at far left. Photographic print, 17.9 x 21.7 cm. (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Miscellany 4
    - "From Lee hill, Devonshire." Pen and ink drawing, 16.5 x 24.4 cm., n.y. Jan 29 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Miscellany 5
    - "Beverley. 3473 Nave W." [Interior of church.] Photographic print, 15.9 x 10.0 cm., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellany 6
    - Ship at dock, published by J. Dickinson, 114 New Bond Street. Lithograph [?], 24.6 x 16.5 cm., 1828 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Miscellany 7
    - Painting of [Moses smiting the rock of Horeb, and making water come out of it?] Photographic print, 12.8 x 26.8 cm. (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Miscellany 8
    - Large square building with arch entrance in Europe or Asia. Photographic print, 19.9 x 25.9 cm., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Miscellany 9
    - Two-story house (same as in Miscellany 2 and 3) with carriage, horses, and five people. Photographic print, 20.7 x 26.7 cm. (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Miscellany 10
    - "Court House, Devon. South View of Court House." Pencil drawing with drawing of man playing [a piano?] on verso: "Mr. [Brownell?]. F. Mores [?] for R.N. School August 12, 1842," 12.0 x 17.4 cm., 1842, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Part III. Box and folder list
  Part III lists the present order of the documents, as boxed.
  - "A group of Victoria Indians taken on board H.M.S. Satellite" Photographic print, 10.5 x 14.6 cm. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Victoria Indians: woman, man, and child. Photographic print, 8.3 x 10.6 cm. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Rose Bank, Dun's hook, Esquimalt, Vancouver Island. The residence of W. A. G. Young, Esq." Photographic print, 11.6 x 15.9 cm. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Hudson's Bay Co. Fort, Victoria, Vancouver Island." Photographic print, 9.5 x 12.3 cm., [1857] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "The American N.W. Boundary Camp, 49th Parallel, Semiahmoo, Gulf of Georgia. The British Possessions." Photographic print, 10.8 x 19.6 cm., [1857 Aug] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Stanley Harbour, Falkland Island. H.M.S. Satellite at anchor." Photographic print, 10.6 x 15.8 cm., [1857 Feb] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Beverley. 3473 Nave W." [Interior of church.] Photographic print, 15.9 x 10.0 cm., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hall, W. H. "Western Coast, Vancouver Isla. by W. H. Hall, Mid. H.M.S. Satellite." Pen and ink drawing, 5.9 x 14.1 cm. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Palmer, J. "Vancouver Island." Pen and ink drawing of camp, 11.4 x 18.3 cm. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Indian canoe & natives." Pen and ink drawing, 9.3 x 17.4 cm. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - [McMurtrie, William?] "Redscaur R[iver]." Pencil drawing, 10.3 x 12.2 cm. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Court House, Devon. South View of Court House." Pencil drawing with drawing of man playing [a piano?] on verso: "Mr. [Brownell?]. F. Mores [?] for R.N. School August 12, 1842," 12.0 x 17.4 cm., 1842, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Robertson, James. "Southern Part of the Head of the Albirni canal. Western Coast, Vancouver Island. Sketched by Jas. Robertson, Masters Assist." Pen and ink drawing, 13.3 x 18.0 cm. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - [McMurtrie, William?] "R[iver] Fraser, "Enterprise" frozen in below point." Pencil drawing, 15.4 x 17.5 cm., 1859 Jan 10 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - [McMurtrie, William?] "Cornish Bar (looking up) Fraser R[iver]." Pencil drawing, 13.3 x 18.0 cm., 1859 Jan 13 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - [McMurtrie, William?] "Fort Yale (looking up)" Pencil drawing, 13.6 x 20.3 cm., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - [McMurtrie, William?] "(Up the) Fraser, Mouth of the Quiquealla R[iver]." Pencil drawing, 13.8 x 20.8 cm. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - [McMurtrie, William?] "From Emery [bank?] (down) the Fraser." Pencil drawing, 13.1 x 17.8 cm., n.y. Jan 21 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - "1st night's encampment in British Columbia." Pen and ink and gray wash drawing, 12.4 x 17.6 cm., 1859 Jul 4 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Two masted ship with note "Drawn from memory by a Songa [Songhee?] Indian (N W Coast of America) to the Northd. of Fort Simpson...." Pencil drawing, 16.3 x 14.2 cm. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Drawing of microorganisms "Found in phosphorescent seawater, magnified 120 diameters." Pen and ink and watercolor drawing, 12.6 x 17.9 cm. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Lowther, Marcus. "[Chinchas?] The Defiance of N.Y. loading." Pen and ink drawing, 11.1 x 15.0 cm., 1854 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "The [stormy?] Petrel -- which surrounded the Satellite on the passage from Valparaiso to Calif." Pen and ink and gray wash drawing, 17.6 x 13.0 cm. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "The little bird which flew on the Satellite's [Port?] and was caught as in a cage when the [Port?] was lowered." Pen and ink and watercolor drawing, 8.5 x 19.0 cm., 1857 Apr 18 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "No. 2. The same as No. 1 only a different view. H.M.S. Satellite." Pen and ink and watercolor drawing, 16.0 x 11.9 cm., [1857] Apr 16 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Tucker, B. "The famous monastery of Megaspeleon...in ancient Achaia...." Pen and ink drawing, 13.2 x 19.3 cm., 1839 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - "From Lee hill, Devonshire." Pen and ink drawing, 16.5 x 24.4 cm., n.y. Jan 29 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ship at dock, published by J. Dickinson, 114 New Bond Street. Lithograph [?], 24.6 x 16.5 cm., 1828 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - [H.M.S. Satellite?] deck, with officer sitting on cannon, four other sailors in view. Photographic print, 17.3 x 21.6 cm., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Fenced in commons [?] with well and harbor in the background with ship at anchor. Photographic print, 17 x 21.5 cm. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - "Nanaimo. Gulf of Georgia, V.I. H.M.S. Satellite." Photographic print, 9.6 x 18.6 cm., [1860 Jun] (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - "Encampment of Royal Marines. North end of San Juan, 13 miles from U.S. detachment. Landed from H.M.S. Satellite." Photographic print, 15.7 x 18.7 cm., [1860 Mar] (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - "Thrakshkayiksh. Fort Simpson. Four months at school." Holograph, with note on side "Original. M.", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - "Valparaiso." Photographic print, 16.3 x 20.9 cm., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - [Valparaiso.] Photographic print, 16.1 x 21 cm., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - [Valparaiso?] Photographic print, 9.6 x 20.8 cm., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - [Valparaiso?] Photographic print, 15.4 x 21.3 cm., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - "Town of Stanley, Falkland Islands." Photographic print, 14.2 x 20.9 cm., 1857 Jul (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Two story house. Photographic print, 15.4 x 20 cm., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Two story house with tree in front and woman at far left. Photographic print, 17.9 x 21.7 cm. (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Alden, J. M. "Harbor -- San Juan Island. Disputed Territory. J. M. Alden, U.S.S. Steamer 'Active.'" Pen and ink and gray wash drawing, 23.6 x 30.6 cm., 1859 Sep (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Four indians, three of them seated, one standing. Pencil, pen and ink and watercolor drawing, 25.5 x 19.2 cm. (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Robertson, James. "Entrance to Albirni canal (Barclay Sound)," "Hills to the Right of Canal (Barclay Sn.)," "Entrance to San Juan Harbr. (Juan-de-Fuca Strait)." Pen and ink drawing, 18.6 x 22.2 cm. (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Robertson, James. "Entrance to Barclay Sound," "Inlet at the Head of Eu-clu-li-at Harb. from anchorage," "Swiss Boy Bay from anchorage." Pen and ink sketch, 18.6 x 23.4 cm. (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Hall, W. H. Points and other landmarks. Four pen and ink drawings, 11.2 x 26.8 cm. (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - "Camp at San Juan Island." Pen and ink and watercolor drawing, 19.8 x 34.6 cm., 1859 Jul 27 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Alden, J. M. "View on Nanaimo River, Vancouver Island." Pen and ink and gray wash drawing, 24.2 x 32.6 cm., 1858 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - [McMurtrie, William?] Three-masted side-wheeler. Pencil drawing, 17.6 x 26.3 cm., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Coastal landmarks, C. Frio and Rio de Janeiro. Pen and ink and watercolor drawings, 22.7 x 28.6 cm. (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Coastal landmarks, Tierra del Fuego, Cape St. Vincent, Magdalena Island. Pen and ink and watercolor drawings, 22.7 x 28.5 cm. (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Coastal landmarks, Capa Froward, Cape Providence, Cape Pillar. Pen and ink and watercolor drawings, 22.7 x 28.5 cm. (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Coastal landmarks, East Falkland and Patagonian Mission House, Rappel Island. Pen and ink and watercolor drawing, 21.7 x 27.2 cm. (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Alden, J.M. Fort Vancouver, Oregon. Watercolor, 23.6 x 30.7 cm., [1854] (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - [Johnson, J.?] "1st encampment of U.S. Land Boundary Commission, Esquimalt, V.I." Photographic print, 15.7 x 21.6 cm. on mount 20.7 x 27.5 cm., [1858 Jul] (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - "Boundary, Mooyie River." Photographic print, 26.2 x 23.2 cm. on mount 34.6 x 27.3 cm (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - [H.M.S. Satellite?] deck, four men standing in the foreground. Photographic print, 19 x 22.1 cm. (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - [H.M.S. Satellite?] deck, two men seated, two men standing. Photographic print, 19.4 x 22.1 cm. (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - "Hudson's Bay Co. Fort Vancouver." Photographic print, 17.8 x 27.2 cm. on mount 27.2 x 34.6 cm., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - One story house with picket fence and two men in front. Photographic print, 22.5 x 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - "Angus McDonald. Factor, Hudson Bay Co." Photographic print, 20.1 x 11.9 cm. on mount 34.5 x 27.3 cm., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - "Part of the U.S. Camp, San Juan Island." Photographic print, 17.4 x 21.9 cm., 1859 Nov 4 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - "Camp of the American Northwest Boundary Commission, Semiahmoo." Photographic print, 22.2 x 29.4 cm., [1857 Aug] (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Painting of [Moses smiting the rock of Horeb, and making water come out of it?] Photographic print, 12.8 x 26.8 cm. (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Large square building with arch entrance in Europe or Asia. Photographic print, 19.9 x 25.9 cm., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Two-story house (same as in Miscellany 2 and 3) with carriage, horses, and five people. Photographic print, 20.7 x 26.7 cm. (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Original covers to scrapbook, with eight of the original leaves, four of them with holograph captions. 43.7 x 26.8 cm., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - "Buildings of the H[udson] B[ay] Co. establishment, San Juan Island." Two photographic prints joined together to form a panorama, 11 cm., [1859 Sep] (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Three one story houses with front porches, with three men in front, and one man in doorway of center house. Watercolor, 25.2 x 34.2 cm. (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Alden, J. M. "At Pt. Grenville, W.T." Watercolor, 17.1 x 26.8 cm. on paper 24.4 x 33.9 cm., 1854 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - British encampment. Watercolor, 17.1 x 47.9 cm., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - "Euclueliat Village, Barclay Sound, Vancouver Island, N.W. Coast. H.M.S. Satellite." Pen and ink and watercolor drawing, 24 x 36 cm., 1859 Mar (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - "[Songhee?] Village. North West Coast Vancouver Island. Barclay Sound. H.M.S. Satellite." Pen and ink and watercolor drawing, 27.3 x 43 cm., 1859 Mar (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - [H.M.S. Satellite, Head of the Albirni Canal, North West Coast of Vancouver Island, Barclay Sound.] Pen and ink and watercolor, 26.4 x 42.7 cm., [1859 Mar 9] (Box 6, Folder 73)